MELISSA J WOMACK

Email: melissa.j.womack@gmail.com | Phone: 512-568-5185 | Dallas, TX 75214

GitHub: https://github.com/Melissajwomack

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/melissajwomack/ Portfolio: https://melissajwomack.github.io/portfolio-v2/

Motivated Bioinformatics Engineer with an aptitude for problem solving. Naturally inquisitive and an analytical thinker. Believer of lifelong learning and continued education. Current computational biology and bioinformatics master's student pursuing the computer science track at University of Texas at Dallas. Graduate of the University of Texas Coding Boot Camp. Previously, while earning a bachelor's degree in microbiology, performed undergraduate research, requiring skills in data analysis and project management. Previous experience in the U.S. Army demonstrating the ability to remain disciplined, detail oriented and a team player. Excited to utilize my technical skills and past experiences to deliver quality products and user experiences.

Technical Skills: C++, R, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Media Queries, JSON, AJAX, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, Passport.js, Handlebars.js, Inquirer.js, React.js, REST, APIs, Materialize, Bootstrap, Git, GitHub, Heroku

EDUCATION

University of Texas, Dallas, TX / August 2019 – Present (Expected – May 2021)

Master of Science in Computational Biology and Bioinformatics - computer science track

University of Texas, Austin, TX / July 2018 – October 2018 Full Stack Web Development Certification Program

Texas State University, San Marcos, TX / January 2015 – May 2018 Bachelor of Science in Microbiology with minor in Biochemistry GPA - 3.76

Austin Community College, Austin, TX / June 2012 – December 2014 Associate of Science in Biology GPA - 3.94

EXPERIENCE

Microbiology Technician

Clinical Pathology Laboratories, Austin, TX / Feb 2019 - Aug 2019

- Processed and handled over 200 clinical samples a day while adhering to safety protocols and ensuring quality control.
- Performed enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays to test for human pathogens in clinical samples.
- Assisted in the identification of clinically relevant organisms using a wide array of biochemical tests.

Instructional Assistant

Texas State University, San Marcos, TX / Jan 2016 - Dec 2016

 Lectured and supervised a college freshman level organismal biology lab under the supervision of a lab coordinator.

United States Army

Food Inspection Specialist / April 2007 - October 2015

- Gained team building and leadership skills while supervising teams of 3-6 people.
- Audited facilities and inspected food, requiring management of documentation and acute attention to detail.
- Facilitated implementation of an inventory database of over 9.3 million dollars of inventory using microsoft excel.